Contact



Cologne, Germany



+4917657835277



yusufolanrewaju9133@gmail.com



M. O Yusuf



https://github.com/olanrewaju-M-Yusuf

Core Skills

- Continuous Integration / Continuous Delivery
- IT Documentation & Debugging
- Linux Administration
- Docker
- Kubernetes
- · Bash Shell Scripting, Python
- · Maven, Jenkins, Tomcat
- Nexus. SonarOube
- Terraform, Ansible, Bitbucket
- AWS, Microsoft Azure
- Git & GitLab
- Prometheus
- Agile Methodologies
- Google Workspace, Microsoft Office Suite
- User Support (Helpdesk-Ticket system)
- HTML, CSS

Soft Skills

- Goal Oriented and Responsible
- Fast Learner and Attentive to Details
- Team Player
- Analytical Reasoning
- Good Communication
- Precision

Language

English

German (B-Level) Yoruba

Hobbies

Olanrewaju M. YUSUF DevOps Engineer

An efficient DevOps Engineer with 2-years professional experience responsible for managing the IT infrastructure and operations. I have worked to ensure that the organization's services are operating at peak performance and are highly available, secure, and cost-effective. I have also been part of a multi-disciplinary team responsible for implementing and managing automated processes for software development, deployment, and maintenance. I also collaborate with other teams to troubleshoot issues, create new features, services, and maintain existing systems

Experience

November 2021 - Present

Oxdit Technologies, Calgary Canada

Junior DevOps Engineer

- Utilizing Docker for building images and containerization of applications as well as Kubernetes for container management and orchestration
- Using AWS resources including EC2, Auto-Scaling, Elastic ELB, S3, Cloud Formation, RDS, DynamoDB, VPC, Route53, SNS. SOS
- Apply Helm as a Kubernetes package manager to deploy and install applications in the clusters
- Deploy Micro-Services using Kubernetes
- Design, develop and implement cloud-based solutions to meet customer requirements
- Used Terraform, Ansible for infrastructure provisioning and configuration i.e. EKS, VPC, Route53, EC2
- Analyze customer requirements and design cost-effective solutions that address their needs
- Develop and document architecture standards, processes and best practices
- Evaluate existing systems and architectures to identify areas of improvement
- Research, evaluate and recommend technology solutions by Developing and maintaining system documentation
- Developing DevOps processes and best practices for automated deployments
- Automating deployment and configuration of software using DevOps tools like Chef, Puppet, and Jenkins
- Collaborating with teams across the organization to ensure successful implementations
- Monitor and troubleshoot production systems to ensure optimal performance

Configure security VPCs in AWS with the use of Cloud formation

Setting up auto triggers like poll SCM, build periodically and web-hooks for periodic build

April - November 2021

Zalando SE, Berlin

UX Researcher

- Designed, planned, and executed user research plans and studies.
- Gathered user feedback on features and applications to inform product design, development, and usability.
- Analyzed user feedback to identify areas of improvement and recommend solutions.
- Developed detailed research reports, including data collection and analysis.
- Tracked and monitor user behavior within the DevOps products and services.
- Identified trends and customer needs to inform product development.
- Collaborated with DevOps team members to ensure research findings are effectively implemented.
- Staved up to date on industry trends and best practices
- Created successful products, services, and experiences for users
- Analyzed user behavior and feedback to create effective strategies for improving user experience
- Supported development of our IT security to avoid downtime and security gaps, e.g. through the administration of servers, firewalls, switches, data backup, fallback systems and the definition of IT security rules
- Supported the Product team to identify, evaluate user data and create strategies for preventing vulnerable activity to ensure solutions are in line with the latest trends
- Conducted interviews and surveys with users, researching user behavior and feedback, and analyzing data to create successful user experience strategies

May 2016 - February 2018

Pebbles Digitals, Lagos Nigeria

IT System Administrator

- Managed and administration of our virtualization environment (VMware), high-performance cluster (gridengine) and networks (VPN, firewall, customer connections, Wifi)
- Supported and administrated of our Linux servers
- Designed and implementation of customized solutions for complex use cases
- Supported the service desk as part of the 2nd level support.
- Provided architecture and configure secure VPCs in AWS including peering of VPC networks
- Analyzed and resolve conflicts related to the merging of source code for GIT.
- · Designed, developed, automated, deployed, scaled and managed both private and public cloud environments
- Optimized and developed IT systems and suggest improvements
- Researched and evaluated new technology solutions.
- Configured Application Life Cycle Management (ALM) tools like JIRA, Confluence to track the progress of the project

EDUCATION

MSc. Sociology and Social Research

University of Cologne, Cologne Germany

Oct. 2018 - Sep. 2021

Sept. 2010 - Feb. 2015

- Qualitative and Quantitative Research, Analysis of Cross-Sectional Data, SQL, Stata and Data Analysis
- Analysis of Longitudinal Data, Structural Equation Modelling & Multi-Level Analysis

BSc. Sociology

Tai Solarin University of Education, Ogun State Nigeria

- Introduction to Quantitative & Qualitative Research
- Sociological Theories, African Social Institution, Labor Laws
- Social Movement and Liberation

CERTIFICATIONS

- AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner
- AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate SAA-C03
- Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals
- SAP Certified Application Associate Business Process Integration with SAP S/4HANA 1809

December 2022 December, 2022 September, 2021

November, 2022

Football, Traveling, Reading, Coding